- Mothers Day today, and I
want to talk about mothers,
but actually I want to
talk more about women
in general this morning.
And I want to kind of
lead up with a movie.
I don't know, old timers
might remember this movie.
Remember the movie, "Pretty Woman?"
Was she ever that young (laughing)?
Julia Roberts, remember her?
Launched her career in this movie.
Roberts plays the part of a prostitute,
but, she's a prostitute with a good heart.
A prostitute with a good heart.
And in this movie, if
you've never seen it,
Richard Gere, the other
co-star in the movie,
he's a lonely but rich business man
that buys her services for a night,
but he ends up falling in love with her.
We fast forward to the end of this movie,
and the end of the movie
has a happy ending.
It finishes on the fire escape here.
Happy ending for these two people.
Now in the story, we find
out that Richard Gere,
you know, is rich.
He can buy fancy clothes.
He can buy cars.
He can buy beauty.
He can buy sex.
But the thing that draws him
to Julia Roberts's character
is that she's honest
with him about himself,
and not just that she's a pretty woman.
That's where the title
comes in, "Pretty Woman."
She's not just a pretty woman.
She has a good heart.
She has an honest heart.
And this is, of course,
the hook in the movie.
He loves her for her
heart, not just her body.
This basically, of course,
is the charm of the movie,
and the message that so
many women have bought into.
The message being, be
beautiful and desirable
on the outside, and be good on the inside.
This pretty woman concept and combination
is promoted in the world as a guarantee
to popularity, and happiness,
and good self-esteem,
and boyfriends, boyfriends.
It also sells a lot of makeup and jeans,
and things like that.
Of course, this desirable-on-the-outside,
good-on-the-inside ideal
works in the movies
and in magazines, but it's not
how the real world operates.
In the real world, we
see that hardly anyone,
especially guys, ever get
past the physical outside
part of a girl in order to bother
discovering the true inner goodness.
And you say, "Why is that?"
Well because men, in the world certainly,
are more interested in sex than
goodness for the most part.
Okay, there are
exceptions, but we all know
that even the good guys have to struggle
to get past just seeing the
physical side of a woman,
and most guys, again, in the world,
just stop right there
and don't go any further.
So what's a girl to do?
So much pressure from TV, and from movies,
from my girlfriends, from guys,
from my own desire to
be noticed, to be liked,
to be loved, to be popular.
You know what I think?
I think that it's about
time that Christian women
of all ages started a revolution.
I say, it's about time Christian women
did something more than
just try to be pretty.
I say, it's about time
women became radicalized
about being Christians,
and started a movement
that created a true shift
in thinking about gender,
and what it means to
be a Christian female,
a Christian woman, in the 21st century.
I say that the time is
overdue for a seismic shift
in how women of faith think
and conduct themselves
so that their true power
can be felt in society.
Now, don't get me wrong.
I'm not talking about the
tired old neo-feminist battle
for women to serve communion,
or preach from the pulpit,
or serve as elders.
I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about a
complete paradigm shift
for the way Christian women
see and project themselves
in the post-modern world.
Sisters, you're being programmed
by the pretty woman
manipulators to be beautiful
and desirable on the outside,
and good and innocent on the inside.
I say, turn the world upside
down in your generation
by going back to the way
that God created you to be.
And that is, good on
the outside (chuckles).
Good on the outside.
Paul writes, "Likewise, I want women,"
and he's talking about Christian women,
"I want women to adorn
themselves with proper clothing,
"modestly and discreetly,
not with braided hair
"and gold or pearls or costly garments,
"but rather by means of good works,
"as is proper for women
making a claim to godliness."
Good on the outside.
Paul is saying, "Cover
yourselves with good works,
"with goodness, with modesty."
This is the outside cover of
a dynamic Christian woman.
Now, don't get me wrong.
It's okay to wear nice
clothes or jewelry, makeup.
But the thing that people
notice are your good works.
The thing that makes you
stand out is your kindness.
Now going back to the
way that God created you
means also, that you're
beautiful in the inside.
1 Peter 3, Peter says, "Your adornment
"must not be merely
external, braiding the hair
"and wearing gold jewelry,
or putting on dresses,
"but let it be the hidden
person of the heart,
"with the imperishable quality of a gentle
"and quiet spirit, which is precious
"in the sight of God."
Good on the outside.
Beautiful on the inside.
And then thirdly,
desirable in the intimacy
of your marriage bed.
Solomon says, "Rejoice in
the wife of your youth,
"let her breasts satisfy you at all times,
"be exhilarated always with her love."
There is a time to be appealing sexually.
God says it's when you become one
with your partner in
marriage, with your husband,
and nowhere else.
There's no call for you to be desirable
to any other man than your husband.
Good on the outside.
Beautiful on the inside.
Desirable in the unity of marriage.
If you begin this revolution,
here's what's going to happen.
Number one, you will break free
of the slavish control of your bodies
by corporate America, and Hollywood,
and social media.
You will once again be in charge of you,
and out of competition with other women,
and the impossible
ideal dangled before you
by those imposters who parade around
as gurus of what you should look like.
Full partnership, true gender justice,
comes only when you are free
from the false image makers.
Good on the outside, unleashes the power
of God's goodness through
you onto the world.
Another thing that will
happen in this revolution.
Beautiful on the inside will
bring peace and security
for your soul.
You see, the true feminine mystique
is only found in the unique nature
of a women's inner beauty.
No spirituality is as
complex and influential
as the power emanating from the heart
of a Christian woman.
A woman has not reached her true potential
until she has begun to cultivate
the depths of her inner
beauty in Christ Jesus.
You see, you're potential is not that you
become as good or successful as men,
but that you reach your
potential as Christians.
There's the key.
And then finally, the
revolution will achieve
what this world and it's
lord want so badly to avoid,
and that is it'll put human sexuality
back into the exclusive
confines of marriage
where it belongs.
Sexuality doesn't belong on a billboard.
It doesn't belong in a magazine.
It doesn't even belong in a movie.
It only belongs in the marriage bed.
That's the only place for it.
Sisters, here are some truths that come
from someone who has
been counseling people
about sexual matters for 40 years,
some basic truth that
you learn after a time.
Truth number one.
The more you preserve
your sexual integrity,
the less pain you will
experience as a single woman,
if you're single.
The more you preserve
your sexual integrity,
the less pain, nevermind about morality,
the less pain that you
will experience as a woman.
Truth number two, the more you preserve
your sexual self, the more precious
this gift will be to your husband.
And truth number three.
The greater your sexual
fidelity in marriage,
the greater potential you have
for a satisfying and
joy-filled sexual experience
within that marriage.
Your precious secret is the
discovery and revelation
of your sexual self to another.
When done within
marriage, it is the source
of endless delight, which
is exactly what Solomon
is saying in the passage
I just read to you
a few moments ago.
Now, I know some of you,
not hearing what I'm saying.
Maybe you don't get it.
Maybe you don't care.
Maybe you just want
church to end (chuckles).
But maybe some of you
like being a pretty woman.
But for those of you who hear me,
this revolution belongs to you.
Don't pay attention to the
smallness of the crowd,
or the awkwardness of the day
because of social distancing.
Listen to what I'm saying to you.
Jesus said the following.
"He presented another
parable to them saying,
"'The kingdom of heaven
is like a mustard seed,
"'which a man took and sowed in his field;
"'and this is smaller
than all other seeds,
"'but when it is full grown, it is larger
"'than the garden plants
and becomes a tree,
"'so that the birds of the air come
"'and nest in its branches.'"
If you get it, if you want
it, you can be that seed,
and begin the revolution
right here, right now,
today even, in this very place.
One day long from now,
you'll remember that
this is the day that you left
the pretty woman complex behind,
and rather reached out
to become a holy woman,
pleasing to God, precious to man,
and at peace with yourself.
I pray that God blesses you, my sisters,
and I sincerely wish
you a happy Mothers Day
to all of those who have had
that wonderful experience.
In closing, let me extend an invitation
to those women and men who have not yet
given their lives to Christ to do this
by expressing your faith in
repentance and in baptism.
And I encourage you to do this now.
Another thing that has always
been ready is the water.
The church spent the
money to get a plumber
to fix the water, to make
sure the water's always ready,
in season, out of season,
the water is always ready,
for those who wish to come to Christ
and express their faith
in repentance and baptism.
And of course, those who need prayer
to be better Christian women,
better Christian mothers,
better Christian men,
better Christian fathers,
the church, the elders, are here always
to pray for your needs.
So if anyone has a need at this time,
we encourage you to make that need known
as we stand and as we sing
our song of encouragement.